Jeffrey Gaskin

Systems Engineer Backup and Recovery - Aegon

West Chester, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jeffrey-Gaskin/39da55e9b7bf50ce

Information Technology Professional with over 18 years experience in backup and recovery, support and implementation within UNIX/Linux windows, VMware environments. Multitasker who excels in fast paced technological environments and consistently demonstrates a solid track record of achieving results. Detail oriented Systems Engineer with a strategic perspective, exceptional analytical skills and the ability to bridge technology effectively to the user community

WORK EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineer Backup and Recovery

Aegon - Exton, PA - August 2006 to Present

Exton, PA 08/06 - Present

Global life insurance, pensions and asset management solutions provider with businesses in over 20 markets in the Americas, Europe and Asia, with 24,000 employees

Systems Engineer Backup and Recovery

Responsible for Enterprise backup/recovery administration utilizing EMC Celerra, Hitachi and Data Domain storage, Veritas NetBackup 7.5.0.5 in a multisite replicated high availability 24/7 production AIX Solaris/Linux, Windows 2003/2008, VMware environment with over 900+ physical and virtual servers

- Lead and implemented multisite NetBackup 5.1 to version 6.5.4 upgrade and consolidation while reducing costs significantly by hardware consolidation and NetBackup license reductions
- Lead and implemented multisite NetBackup 6.5.4 to version 7.1 upgrade
- Implemented a multisite NetBackup 7.1 to version 7.5.0.5 upgrade
- Implemented VMware vStorage API backup solution utilizing NetBackup
- Data Domain 690 administration in a multisite replicated environment
- Multisite Disaster Recovery planning and testing Work with all levels of business users and Executivelevel management to ensure security compliancy for backups and DR recovery at off-site location. Research implement and support new backup solutions to met the growing needs and goals of the company
- Winchester & Hitachi AMS 200 disk storage support
- Support & administration of StorageTek L700e and IBM 3584 tape libraries
- Responsible for installing, configuring, administering, upgrading and maintaining the enterprise backup infrastructure; configuring backup clients, maintaining backup windows, schedules, rotations and retention policies, reporting and troubleshooting and resolving backup issues. Overseeing and improvement of process and procedures for backup/recovery and disaster recovery management

Support Center Analyst

Genesis Health Ventures - Kennett Square, PA - March 2006 to August 2006

Kennett Square, PA 03/06 - 08/06

One of the nation's largest skilled nursing and rehabilitation therapy providers with more then 400 Skilled Nursing Centers and Assisted/Senior Living Communities located in 28 states with 80,000 employees.

Support Center Analyst

Responsible for remote Windows 2000/XP desktop support via SMS & VNC, SalesLogix ticket creation, application and printer installation,

- Active Directory administration
- network troubleshooting and end user remote support

IT Security Analyst

GlaxoSmithKline - King of Prussia, PA - December 2005 to December 2005

King of Prussia, PA 12/05 - 12/05

Global pharmaceuticals with offices in more than 115 countries, major research centre's in the UK, USA, Spain, Belgium and China and an extensive manufacturing network with 87 sites globally.

IT Security Analyst

Responsible for daily virus & malware detection, troubleshooting & tracking utilizing Symantec Enterprise Security Architecture & Symantec Anti Virus 10.0 Corporate Edition in the GSK global IT environment

- Managing & providing infrastructure protecting security processes
- Development & documentation of SESA reports & metrics
- Intelligence gathering & tracking, threat publication & assessment
- · Opening of Remedy incident tracking tickets and solving customer generated tickets

Network/Systems Administrator

Bairnco - Bear, DE - September 2005 to November 2005

Responsible for Windows NT and Network infrastructure Administration in a 200 user multiple domain, Dell PowerEdge server administration, staging, implementation and support

- Trend Micro Anti virus, Veritas Backup Exec and Exchange 5.5 administration
- Desktop support of Windows XP, 2000 and NT workstations
- Zebra printer and wireless Network support
- Responsible for all hardware and software purchasing
- Responsible for troubleshooting, resolution and documentation of Network connectivity, printing and software issues

Systems Support Specialist

Eastern National - Fort Washington, PA - October 2004 to July 2005

Fort Washington, PA 10/04 - 07/05

Non Profit cooperating association, that supports the National Park Service by procuring, distributing and selling educational material in retail outlets located in national parks

Systems Support Specialist

Responsible for System Administration, staging and support of Windows NT/2000, 2003 and Linux servers, Symantec Antivirus administration, computer hardware and software configuration, procurement and implementation, Network support

- Troubleshooting & documentation of software applications, printing issues, PC hardware and Network connectivity and firewall problems
- Responsible for NT/2000 2003 server maintenance, OS patching, backups utilizing BrightStor ARCserve & Backup Exec & hardware & software upgrades
- Desktop support of XP Pro workstations Ghosting, PBX, IIS Web server, SQL server and POS support
- Exchange 5.5 Administration and support

Systems Administrator

TACWORLDWIDE - Collegeville, PA - April 2004 to October 2004

Responsible for Systems Administration of Windows 2000/NT, VMware ESX Servers in a Sun Unix, Red Hat Linux environment

- Exchange 5.5 and 2000 e-mail recovery and administration utilizing ARCserve, Veritas NetBackup, Backup Exec and Legato NetWorker for Exchange Server
- Exchange recovery on Sun servers running SunOS 5.8 utilizing Legato NetWorker
- Support of StorageTek L700e tape libraries and training of new Administrators

Windows/Unix Server Support Analyst

Innovantage Agilent Technologies - Wilmington, DE - October 2002 to June 2003

Wilmington, DE 10/02 - 06/03

The world's premier measurement company providing Chemical Analysis, Life Sciences, Diagnostics and Genomics, and Electronic Measurement with 20,500 employees and \$6.9 billion U.S revenue Windows/Unix Server Support Analyst

Responsible for the Administration of 30 Windows NT/2000 Servers for R&D. Server installation, configuration & staging, monitoring, rollouts, upgrades, patching, and migrations in a multi-domain environment

- Network support and troubleshooting, IIS Server support
- Responsible for Windows NT/2000 server backups, maintenance, OS patches and hardware upgrades
- Responsible for data center maintenance
- Windows NT/2000 & XP workstation desktop and lab workstation support, installation and configuration
- Responsible for Symantec System Center and Norton Antivirus Corporate Edition implementation and administration, virus detection and removal
- Managed STAR server hardware/software Inventory Asset Management project for R&D group

Independent Consultant

Compaq Evo - August 2001 to October 2002

Desktop Specialist

- Implemented the rollout and imaging of 200 Compaq Evo desktop PCs and the redeployment of Deskpro 4000 PCs utilizing Symantec Ghost 7.5 at MBNA
- Implemented PC asset inventory and Intel LANDesk Management Suite software upgrades on 600+ node network at Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania
- Preparation and study for HP-UX Administration certification

Systems Administrator

Electronic Data Systems/GMAC - Horsham, PA - January 2001 to August 2001

Enterprise Systems Management Group)

Responsible for network infrastructure management, monitoring, troubleshooting, performance monitoring, capacity planning, and device utilization using Unicenter TNG in an NT, Windows 2000 HP-UX environment

- Implementation of Unicenter TNG on a 250+ server LAN/WAN with 100+ offices around the country
- Daily operation and upkeep of Unicenter maps and objects and Unicenter administration
- Agent installation and configuration on NT, 2000 and HP-UX servers
- Installed and configured Agents, set thresholds alerts and monitored Oracle and MS SQL databases and servers
- Performance trend analysis, job scheduling using AutoSys
- Implemented discoveries of subnets and servers
- Business Process View implementations
- Utilized Report Manager to provide various reports to requesting departments
- Implemented Unicenter TNG patches, policy modification and rollouts
- BayStack ARN Router configuration

Advanced Systems Engineer

SHARED MEDICAL SYSTEMS - Malvern, PA - 1996 to October 2000

Malvern, PA 1996 - 10/00

One of the world's largest suppliers to the healthcare industry of medical imaging, laboratory diagnostics, medical information technology and hearing aids

Advanced Systems Engineer

Implemented Microsoft SNA Server and Novell SAA gateways for LAN/WAN connectivity to IBM mainframe host via TCP/IP, DLC 802.2 & SDLC protocols. Installed NetWare and SNA clients on NT workstations and configured 3270 and TN3270 emulation. Performed NT, Unicenter and Novell 4x and 5x installation and administration. Provided project management, network design, implementation and technical support to SMS Field Engineers. Provided LAN/WAN network management performance and troubleshooting support utilizing HP-Openview, Concord Network Health, NetView and Unicenter TNG. Configured IBM Netfinity & Compaq ProLiant servers. Documented hardware/software installation and problem resolutions for field engineers. Received Cisco Router training

- Produced biannual Implementers CD's containing latest Microsoft, Novell, DB2, Cisco and Citrix Service Packs which increased our Field Engineers productivity
- Coordinated all LRS VPS AnyQueue installations
- Performed network assessments with Network Associates Sniffer and created Network Health Reports
- Tested new software releases of Attachmate and Rumba terminal emulators for compatibility within the SMS environment

Systems & Technology Analyst

REED SMITH SHAW & McCLAY - Philadelphia, PA - 1994 to 1996

Philadelphia, PA 1994 - 1996

Global law firm with coast-to-coast offices in the United States, as well as in Europe, Asia and the Middle East Systems & Technology Analyst

Responsible for workstation, installation configuration, management, Novell Administration and desktop support of 100 plus node Novell 4.10 network, LAN/WAN utilizing Cabletron hubs and Cisco routers. Provided Lotus Notes, GroupWise OS/2 e-mail Gateway and Windows NT SQL Server administration. Supported SpectraLogic robotic tape backup with Palindrome Storage Manager, MS Office, DaVinci eMail, Rightfax, PC Docs and ECCO Pro personal manager

- UNIX System Administrator of two AT&T UNIX systems utilizing OfficePower 7.02 and x.400 based e-mail
- Prepared department budget, handled staff scheduling, hiring, project management and hardware and software purchasing
- · Performed system backups, restores, archiving and Disaster Recovery planning and implementation
- Managed network cabling project for the Philadelphia and New Jersey offices
- Managed and implemented successful hardware, software & user migration from AT&T UNIX to Novell 4.10
- · Responsible for Windows NT server Administration and hardware and software purchasing

Systems Specialist

ASA LEGAL SYSTEMS INC - Blue Bell, PA - 1992 to 1994

Installed UNIX, MS-DOS/Novell and VMS based proprietary legal accounting software; hardware and software system integration, configuration and support. Implemented TCP/IP, Pathworks, and LAN design and installation. Performed AIX UNIX Administration on IBM RS/6000s and SCO UNIX System Administration. UNIX shell scripting

EDUCATION

Baccalaureate in Computer Science

BEAVER COLLEGE - Glenside, PA 1984

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science

Temple University - Philadelphia, PA 1981

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeffrey-gaskin/a/564/926

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Operating Systems: Windows [...] AIX, Solaris, UNIX/Linux, VMware, Novell NetWare

Storage: Data Domain, EMC Celerra, Hitachi

Monitoring Tools: CA Unicenter TNG, NetView, HP OpenView

Applications: NetBackup, Backup Exec Symantec Anti Virus administration BMC Remedy Incident management /Problem and Change management